Ryan Knight

Software Developer

Spokane, WA (509)-957-9777 ryan.knight09@outlook.com https://ryan-knight.web.app

About me

I have been writing software for roughly five years and consider myself a front end developer. I like to think I am a full stack front end developer due to my ability to build robust gql back end for front end servers, as well as my React development experience. I have used everything from UI kits like Material UI to vanilla html / css. For the last few years I have been all about Graphql and React.

Experience

August 2021-Present

Front End Tech Lead - EvolveMep.

Full stack front end lead for the entire evolve product line. The product consists of eight module apps, each with their own dedicated teams. Each app is pulled together via a container application. It is a very progressive AWS first approach.

Daily activities include architecture design, review pull requests, meetings with UX and PM, tasking out jira tickets for module team leads, and lighthouse (beta) customer meetings where we gather customer requirements.

- Mono repo with nx.dev
 - Storybook management
 - Cypress E2E integrations
 - Shared libs
 - Module federation for remote apps
- React, React Router, React Form Hooks
- Apollo client data layer for state management
- AWS Appsync that wraps a REST back end via vtl resolvers.

April 2019-2021

Front End Developer - StorageCraft Technology Corp.

Front end project lead for Saas Cloud Backup and Recovery for O365, G-suit. Responsibilities include architecting Graphql data server, and React client. Client stack: React, React Router, Jest, Apollo Client 3 (comprehensive data layer solution: fetching, caching, state management). GQL server stack: (Apollo, express, jest, firebase / firestore / real time database).

June 2018 - March 2019

Software Engineering Intern - Exact Sciences Laboratory Information Systems

My main role was to work on code optimizations inside of our application as well as building automated QA test environment features for our business analysts. Most of my development was in Java, Javascript, and various JS frameworks such as React.

Sep 2017 - 2018

Teaching Assistant - Eastern Washington University

Tutoring and grading student assignments in the Java development courses.

Education

Sept 2015 - 2019

Eastern Washington University - Cheney , Wa - B.S Computer Science

- Heavy emphasis on OOP in Java, relational database, data structure ect.
- Web development with React

Sept 2009 - June 2011

Spokane Falls Community College - Spokane, Wa - AAS Audio Engineering

Extensive background in sound production, signal processing, system hardware design set up, and post production.

Projects

Portfolio V1: (React, Stylized Components)

A single page, smooth scrolling and responsive portfolio app. A fancy version of my resume built with React, and vanilla html / css..

https://github.com/ryanknight09/portfolio

References

Professional references available upon request please.